SURYA NARAYANAN

lgsurya30@gmail.com | +91-6369724601 | Linkedin | Website | Bengaluru,India

SUMMARY

A Creative Designer having 4+ years of experience in optimising user experience through innovative solutions, Gathering user requirements, Designing graphic elements, Building navigation components. Combine UX thinking with design execution, to produce usable and intuitive user interfaces.

EXPERIENCE

Senior UX/UI Designer at eMudhra Technology Limited, Bengaluru, KA

May 2021 - Present

- Taking Ownership of the the multiple product for design.
- Mentor art direction to other designers by maintaining the proper design system and flows.
- Driven to discover and bring quantitative hypotheses to drive the product metrics.
- Giving form to ideas by being the voice of our UI design decisions e.g. UI Kits, Navigation bars, widgets and building components, Through wire-framing, pixel perfect designs and prototyping, style guides and Pattern libraries.
- Collaborate with Vice President, Product Managers and Team Leaders to ensure a solid and continuously improving product life cycle.
- Proven design experience as a Mobile App designer and front end web developer.
- Design and implement A/B tests to validate changes and measure their impact.

Accomplishments

- Indian Air force (IAF) cloud storage internal desktop application designed and delivered with proper design system, Organized structural layout, wireframing, high quality visual and UI design.
- Implementing product variant redesigns has successfully profited 20% increase in the organization with clear presentations of design systems and mockups for mobile apps

UX/UI Designer at CIOC FMCG Private Limited, Bengaluru, KA

Jan 2020 - May 2021

- Developing user friendly interfaces and interaction flows of 10+ applications for mobile and web applications.
- Collaborating with team for consistency of the user experience while taking it step by step to the next level
- Experience in SaaS platforms, B2B, B2C and/or enterprise products...
- · Execute various visual design stages from concept to final hand-off development

Accomplishments

 Interact and Successfully completed clients requirement both domestic and International from scratch work. Get additional rewards for dedicated design over completion of client projects and achieved 30% increase in company's growth with positive clients feedbacks.

UX Designer at Haso Technology Private Limited, Madurai, TN

Aug 2019 - Dec 2019

- Practiced UX research under a senior UX Designer, designing daily UI design tasks.
- Get in touch with stake holders to understand what is the basic requirements and how to develop a product.
- Have strong understanding of User Experience Design and Design Thinking process
- Engage working on Brochures, Logos, illustrations and vector graphics.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering: Electronics and Communication Engineering

Aug 2015 - May 2019

K.L.N College of Engineering.

TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES

Design Tools: Figma, Photoshop, Illustrator, Adobe XD, Blender, After effects, InVision, UXTweek, Affinity Designer

Skills: UX Research, User Interviews, Survey, User centeredDesign process like Define, Empathise, Ideate, User flow, Sketches, Low & High fidelity wireframe, Visual Design, Prototyping, Mockups, Mood-board, Illustrations.

Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, Javascript

Operating Systems: Mac, Windows